Guide to the Jacques Vallee UFO and paranormal phenomena papers MS 672
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jacques Vallee UFO and paranormal phenomena papers
1960-2015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Vallee, Jacques
MS 672
38 Linear Feet
The collection includes background files, correspondence, field notes, and press documents collected by Vallee between 1960 and 2015.
Biographical / Historical
Jacques Vallée is a computer scientist, author, ufologist and astronomer conducting research in UFO topics.
Scope and Contents
Background files include relevant topics, general cases, social trends, cults, related phenomena, scientific topics relevant to ufology, assembled by Vallee in support of his research over the years. Also contains field notes and press documents about related topics such as cattle mutilations, and face-to-face meetings of NIDS and BAASS, as well as various research proposals.
Correspondence includes letters exchanged with Aime Michel, Dr. Hynek, Dr. Guerin, and many leading researchers and investigators, starting in the late 1950s to the mid 2010s.
Analysis files are planned for donation in the future, and will include research studies, often field investigations or document research about specific UFO topics.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is restricted by request of the donor for ten years from the date of the gift. The opening date will be Jan. 1, 2031. Several specific academic exceptions have been made and are articulated in the deed of gift. Contact woodson@rice.edu for details.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Janques Valle in 2018, via Dr. Jeffrey Kripal, Dept. of Religion, Rice University.
Index Terms
Subjects
Unidentified flying objects; Parapsychology
Document Types
videotapes; audiotapes; reports; letters (correspondence); notes
- Series: Background
  - Denzler Abduction Survey (B1-B2) (Box 1, Box 2)
  - Background data by geography (B3) (Box 3)
    - Argentina (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Argentina: Santa Fe Province (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Argentina: Mendoza, April 22, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Argentina: UFO Press newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Argentina: CEFAI (periodical) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Argentina: CODOVINI (periodical) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Brazil (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Brazil: May 20, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Brazil: OUNI Documento (periodical) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Caribbean Wave, February 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Chile (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Colombia (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Costa Rica (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Guyana: L. Wellington, Fall 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Latin America (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Canada (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Czechoslavakia (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - New Zealand (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Germany (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Italy (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Poland (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Spain (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Switzerland (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Russia (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
    - South Africa: Jan. 3, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - China (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Japan (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - New York: Cosmic Frontiers (periodical) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Background data by geography (B4) (Box 4)
  - Background data, France (B5) (Box 5)
  - Background data by history (B6) (Box 6, Box 7)
  - UFO organizations, 20th century, United States (B7) (Box 8)
  - UFO organizations, 20th century (B8) (Box 9)
  - Background data: Physical effects and theories (B9) (Box 10)
  - Databases (B10) (Box 11)
  - Audio tapes (B11) (Box 12)
  - UFO video programs (B12) (Box 13)
  - Cattle mutilations (B13) (Box 14)
  - UFO element analysis, Peter Sturrock et al (B14) (Box 15)
  - Books (B17-B18) (Box 16, Box 17)
  - UFO books (B19) (Box 18)
  - Publications about UFOs and the paranormal (Box 19)
  - Professional publications (B20) (Box 20)
- Series: Correspondence
  - Correspondence (C1) (Box 21)
    - 1. Hynek-Vallée correspondence — The 1960s decade to 1970 (incl.)
    - 2. Hynek-Vallée correspondence — The 1970s and 1980s
    - 3. Hynek's publications and statements (partial collection)
    - 4. Eglin Air Force Base speech, 27 April 1960
    - 5. Dr. J. Allen Hynek — remembered: Obituaries (+ 27 Apr.1986) and related documents
    - 6. Mimi Hynek documents
    - 7. The AFFA-CIA channeling of 9 July 1959
    - 8. Other material relevant to Dr. Hynek
    - 9. Contracts, secrets, official correspondence
    - 10. Media coverage
    - 11. The Robertson Panel and the "Pentacle Memorandum" — January 1953
    - 1. Vallée-Michel correspondence — 1958-1962
    - 2. Vallée-Michel correspondence — 1962-1965
    - 3. Vallée-Michel correspondence — 1966-1969
    - 4. Vallée-Michel correspondence — 1970-1973
    - 5. Vallée-Michel correspondence — 1975-1979
    - 6. Vallée-Michel correspondence — 1980 to (+ 28 Dec.1992)
    - 7. Aimé Michel: Relevant material
  - Correspondence (unlabeled) (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, American Research (C4) (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, American Research (C5) (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, American Research (C6) (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, American Research (C7) (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, French Research (C8) (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, French Research (C9) (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, International Research (C9) (Box 29)
  - Correspondence: Witnesses and Psychics (Box 30)
  - Correspondence: unlabeled (Box 31, Box 32)
- Series: Case files (Boxes 33-38)
  - Vallee box A1 (Box 33)
    - A1. Vacuum Cleaner (Box 33)
    - A2. Neo Nazi (Box 33)
    - A3. Baptism Beam (Box 33)
    - A4. Holy Ghost (Box 33)
    - A5. Camera Conference. Part I (Box 33)
    - A6. Camera Conference. Part II (Box 33)
    - A7. Camera Conference. Part III (Box 33)
    - A8. Mount Athos (Box 33)
    - A9. Pontoise Abduction. Part I (Box 33)
    - A10. Pontoise Abduction. Part II (Box 33)
    - A11. Pontoise Abduction. Part III (Box 33)
    - A12. Pontoise Abduction. Part IV (Box 33)
    - A13. Pontoise Abduction. Part V (Box 33)
    - A14. Pontoise Abduction. Part VI (Box 33)
    - A15. Heaven's Gate (Box 33)
    - A16. Gyro Beams (Box 33)
    - A17. Panic Ball (Box 33)
    - A18. Teesdale Inheritance (Box 33)
    - A19. Mosaic Mission, part I (Box 33)
    - A20. Mosaic Mission, part II (Box 33)
    - A21. Cosmic Watchers (Box 33)
    - A22. Strip Tease. (UMMO) (Box 33)
    - A23. Strip Tease. (UMMO) (Box 33)
    - A24. Strip Tease. (UMMO) (Box 33)
    - A25. Triple Weed (Box 33)
    - A26. Valentich Uptake (Box 33)
    - A27. Trash Heap. Part I (Box 33)
    - A28. Trash Heap. Part II (Box 33)
  - Vallee box A2 (Box 34)
    - A29. Junk Yard (Box 34)
    - A30. Cipher Robot (Box 34)
    - A31. Crystal Node (Box 34)
    - A32. Baboon Glow (Box 34)
    - A33. Claret Seeker (Box 34)
    - A34. Survey East (Box 34)
    - A35. Camper Mate (Box 34)
    - A36. Twin Pines (Box 34)
    - A37. Brain Drain (Box 34)
    - A38. Channel Zero (Box 34)
    - A39. Bartholomew Trip (Box 34)
    - A40. Angel Dust (Box 34)
    - A41. Diver Archipel (Box 34)
    - A42. Kangaroo Court (Box 34)
    - A43. Formula Ganimedes (Box 34)
    - A44. Shiny Face (Box 34)
    - A45. Cat Widow (Box 34)
    - A46. Circus Artist (Box 34)
    - A47. Agent Orange (Box 34)
    - A48. Triple Ring (Box 34)
    - A49. Inner Voice (Box 34)
    - A50. Locksmith Control (Box 34)
    - A51. Fire Square (Box 34)
    - A52. Silver Ray (Box 34)
    - A53. Monitor Galore (Box 34)
    - A54. Costa Rica (Box 34)
    - A55. Yellow Ice (Box 34)
    - A56. Brown Technology (Box 34)
    - A57. Reform Club (Box 34)
    - A58. Fort Palisade (Box 34)
    - A59. High Newton (Box 34)
    - A60. Arcturus Rising (Box 34)
    - A61. Planet Vulcan (Box 34)
  - Vallee box A3 (Box 35)
    - A64. Egyptian Divinity (Box 35)
    - A65. Santa Cruz (Box 35)
    - A66. Fast Walkers (Box 35)
    - A67. Donald Menzel (Box 35)
    - A68. God Trap (Box 35)
    - A69. Scrambled Eggs (Box 35)
    - A70. Tin Can (Box 35)
    - A71. Shoe Factory (Box 35)
    - A72. Blank Slate (Box 35)
    - A73. Mental Contact (Box 35)
    - A74. Sans Souci (Box 35)
    - A75. Ringing Rocks (Box 35)
    - A76. Space Lady (Box 35)
    - A77. Bentwaters Case (Box 35)
    - A78. Space Graph (Box 35)
    - A79. Cooper Culprits (Box 35)
    - A80. Shady Lane (Box 35)
    - A81. Shamanic Journey (Box 35)
    - A82. Skeptic Tank (Box 35)
    - A83. Morocco Mary (Box 35)
    - A84. Olympus Bengal (Box 35)
    - A85. Area 51 (Box 35)
    - A86. Orphan King. Part I (Box 35)
    - A87. Orphan King. Part II (Box 35)
    - A88. Vorilhon Raël (Box 35)
    - A89. Cosmic Fraternity (Box 35)
    - A90. Unarius Society (Box 35)
    - A91. Dark Galaxy (Box 35)
  - Vallee box A4 (Box 36)
    - A92. Psi Tech (Box 36)
    - A93. Moon Structures (Box 36)
    - A94. Red Umbrella (Box 36)
    - A95. Northern Control (Box 36)
    - A96. Malta Cross and the Circle of the Ancient Gods (Box 36)
    - A97. Snake Bite (Box 36)
    - A98. Brother Seven (Box 36)
    - A99. Sananda Temple (Box 36)
    - A100. Grupo Rama (Box 36)
    - A101. Religious Angles (Box 36)
    - A102. Granada Paradise (Box 36)
    - A103. Urantia Credo (Box 36)
    - A104. Universal League (Box 36)
    - A105. Silence Gallery (Box 36)
    - A106. Spiritual Frontier (Box 36)
    - A107. Stelle Group (Box 36)
    - A108. World Family (Box 36)
    - A109. Utopia Formula (Box 36)
    - A110. Khabarah Khoom (Box 36)
    - A111. Manna Machine (Box 36)
    - A112. Searle Effect (Box 36)
    - A113. Sub Genius (Box 36)
    - A114. Psycho Blue (Box 36)
    - A115. Radio Beyond (Box 36)
    - A116. Father June (Box 36)
    - A117. Special Operations (Box 36)
    - A118. Human Potential (Box 36)
    - A119. Downward Spiral (Box 36)
    - A120. High Provence (Box 36)
    - A121. Washington Vision (Box 36)
    - A122. Sister Exodus (Box 36)
    - A123. Shell Game. (Closed file, confidential) (Box 36)
    - A124. Project Merida (Box 36)
    - A125. Harvard Square (Box 36)
  - Vallee box A5 (Box 37)
    - A126. Manhattan Transfer (Box 37)
    - A127. Iron Mountain (Box 37)
    - A128. Prima Materia (Box 37)
    - A129. Model Airplane (Box 37)
    - A130. Dead Scientists (Box 37)
    - A131. Pandora's Box (Box 37)
    - A132. Texas Invictus (Box 37)
    - A133. Guinea Pig (Box 37)
    - A134. Pine Bush (Box 37)
    - A135. Rosary Lights (Box 37)
    - A136. Montauk Experiment (Box 37)
    - A137. Mercedes Driver (Box 37)
    - A138. Space Hoaxes (Box 37)
    - A139. Magickal Theories (Box 37)
    - A140. Garnet Star (Box 37)
    - A141. Data Base (Box 37)
    - A142. Bush Man (Box 37)
    - A143. SETI Project (Box 37)
    - A144. Nebula Exchange (Box 37)
    - A145. Belgian Triangles (Box 37)
    - A146. Propeller Heads (Box 37)
    - A147. Aurora Beamer (Box 37)
    - A148. Channel Simona (Box 37)
    - A149. Airship Analysis (Box 37)
    - A150. Modern Apparition (Box 37)
    - A151. Clear Lake (Box 37)
    - A152. Project Hessdalen (Box 37)
    - A153. Jack Sarfatti. Part 1 of 3 (Box 37)
    - A153. Jack Sarfatti. Part 2 of 3 (Box 37)
    - A153. Jack Sarfatti. Part 3 of 3 (Box 37)
    - A154. Cotton Gin. (Closed file, confidential) (Box 37)
    - A155. Purple Ice. (Closed file, confidential) (Box 37)
    - A156. Rising Sun (Box 37)
    - A157. Underground Risin (Box 37)
    - A158. Alien Autopsy (Box 37)
    - A159. Clone Family (Box 37)
    - A160. Cloud Rider (Box 37)
    - A161. Gordon Novell (Box 37)
    - A162. Pocantico Hills (Box 37)
    - A163. European Parliament (Box 37)
  - Vallee box A6 (Box 38)
    - A164. Hot Water. (Closed file, confidential) (Box 38)
    - A165. Steady Signal (Box 38)
    - A166. McDonald writing (Box 38)
    - A167. Project Kairos (Box 38)
    - A168. Buffalo Testing (Box 38)
    - A169. Secret Onion (Box 38)
    - A170. Minot Bomber (Box 38)
    - A171. Hommes Noirs (Box 38)
    - A172. Private Bliss (Box 38)
    - A173. Passion Karadoni (Box 38)
    - A174. Physics Department (Box 38)
    - A175. Golden Pellet (Box 38)
    - A176. First Kingdo (Box 38)
    - A177. Photo Analysi (Box 38)
    - A178. Rachel's Eyes (Box 38)
    - A179. Vacuum Energ (Box 38)
    - A180. Virgin Vision (Box 38)
    - A181. Shannon Video (Box 38)
    - A182. Light Triangle (Box 38)
    - A183. Contact Aveyro (Box 38)
    - A184. Egryn Flap (Box 38)
    - A185. Third Displacement (Box 38)
    - A186. Viton Griffith (Box 38)
    - A187. Sanderson Theory (Box 38)
    - A188. Mona Lisa (Box 38)
    - A189. Spiritual Deceit (Box 38)
    - A190. Saucer Syndrome (Box 38)
    - A191. Bag Lady (Box 38)
    - A192. Bottle Hollow (Box 38)
    - A193. Insect Implan (Box 38)
    - A194. Nice Promenade (Box 38)
    - A195. French Methods (Box 38)
    - A196. Shaman Overlap (Box 38)
    - A197. Post Mortem (Box 38)
    - A198. Arnold Data (Box 38)
    - A199. Calcium Ions (Box 38)
    - A200. Majestic Twelve (Box 38)